Guide to the George Henry Nettleton Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
George Henry Nettleton papers
1819-1959
MS 473
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
19.25
The papers consist of correspondence, subject files, diaries, speeches and writings, and memorabilia chiefly relating to George Henry Nettleton's career as professor of English at Yale, his activities with the Yale Bureau in Paris and the American University Union, and his scholarly research and writings.
Nettleton, George Henry, 1874-1959
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of the estate of George H. Nettleton, 1959; Mary Treat Nettleton Haight, 1987; and George D. Glazer, 1995, and Minot B. Nettleton, 2002.
Arrangement
Arranged in five series and two additions: I. Correspondence, 1884-1955. II. Subject Files, 1917-1945. III. Diaries, 1899-1956. IV. Speeches and Writings, 1915-1951. V. Memorabilia, 1893-1945.
Scope and Contents
The George Henry Nettleton Papers contain correspondence, subject files, diaries, speeches and writings, and memorabilia chiefly relating to Nettleton's career as professor of English at Yale and his activities with the Yale Bureau and the American University Union. The papers were the gift of the estate of George H. Nettleton (1959) and of Mary Treat Nettleton Haight (1987). The fourteen linear feet of papers are arranged in five series: I. Correspondence, 1884-1955; II. Subject Files, 1917-1945; III. Diaries, 1899-1956; IV. Speeches and Writings, 1915-1951; V. Memorabilia, 1893-1945.
Series I, CORRESPONDENCE, contains two subseries: Personal Correspondence and Professional Correspondence. The bulk of the personal correspondence is dated 1884-1902 and consists of letters written between George Henry Nettleton, his mother Mary Ellen Tucker Nettleton, and his sister Annie Tucker Nettleton. The letters relate to George Nettleton's undergraduate and graduate studies as well as extracurricular activities at Yale, and his subsequent Yale instructorship; Annie Tucker Nettleton's senior year at the Abbot Academy in Andover, Massachusetts, and her elementary school and kindergarden teaching career in North Rochester and Boston, Massachusetts; and his mother's home life in Boston and Dorchester, Massachusetts.
Personal correspondence dating from 1902-1950 is dominated by correspondence between Nettleton and his wife Mary Clark Treat Nettleton, written during Professor Nettleton's travels to England and Europe. The bulk of the letters from this period date from 1917 to 1919 and document Nettleton's experiences as director of the Yale Bureau in Paris and the American University Union, and Mrs. Nettleton's experiences during World War I in the New Haven, Connecticut, area. Correspondence between the Nettletons and their friends William Lyon and Annabel Phelps is also contained in this subseries.
The bulk of the professional correspondence relates to Nettleton's work with the Yale Bureau in Paris and the American University Union. Correspondents include Robert Woods Bliss, John William Cunliffe, Paul van Dyke, H.S. Krans, Van Rensselaer Lansingh, Anson Phelps Stokes, and Henry B. Thompson. Letters pertaining to Nettleton's scholarly research and writing, and his activities as contributing editor of Book of the Yale Pageant and editor of Yale in the World War are also contained in the subseries.
Professional correspondence relating to Nettleton's teaching and administrative career includes letters regarding war time military courses at Yale (1917), and the Committee on the General Needs of the College (1923-1924, 1934).
The bulk of Series II, SUBJECT FILES, dates from 1917-1937 and relates to the Yale Bureau in Paris and the Amerian University Union. Minutes of meetings, financial records, and reports are contained in these files. In addition, files dating from 1919-1939 that relate to Nettleton's activities on Yale University committees, as dean of Yale College, and as professor of English are included in the series.
The diaries within Series III contain brief notations of Nettleton's business, social, and leisure activities. Included in this series is a diary in which Nettleton described a European tour in 1899.
Series IV, SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, contains manuscripts and typescripts of books, articles, and speeches by George Nettleton. The bulk of the material relates to an unpublished work on the history of Yale and the publications, Yale in the World War and The Yale Pageant. In addition, there is one folder containing miscellaneous poems, articles, and notes dated 1939-1940, and undated by other writers.
Series V, MEMORABILIA, contains photographs, postcards, and printed material chiefly relating to the American University Union and World War I. An account book from Nettleton's sophomore year at Yale (1893-1894) is also included in this series.
Biographical / Historical
George Henry Nettleton was born on July 16, 1874, in Boston, Massachusetts, the son of Boston attorney Edward Payson Nettleton and Mary Ellen Tucker Nettleton. He attended the Boston Latin School (1886-1889) and Phillips-Andover Academy (1889-1892), and received the B.A. (1896) and the Ph.D. (1900) from Yale University, and an honorary Litt.D. (1920) from Baylor University. As an undergraduate at Yale, Nettleton was an editor of the Yale Courant and of the Lit, a member of Chi Delta Theta, the Yale Union, the Cap and Gown Committee, Kappa Psi, Psi U, and Scroll and Key, and was elected to Phi Beta Kappa.
Nettleton was instructor (1898), assistant professor (1906-1916), and professor (1916-1943) of English, and chairman of the English department (1921-1931) at Yale. From 1937-1939 he was dean of Yale College. During the academic year 1922-1923, he served as acting president of Vassar College.
In 1917 Nettleton was appointed director of the Yale Bureau in Paris, a meeting place for Yale-affiliated servicemen. From 1917-1919, Nettleton directed the American University Union in Europe. This organization coordinated the efforts of a number of American universities in establishing facilities to provide meeting, dining, and overnight accommodations, as well as cultural activities, in Paris, London, and Rome for American servicemen. Nettleton continued to be involved in the activities of the American University Union after the war, when, under the Institute of International Education and the American Council on Education, the Paris and London divisions of the union evolved into educational and cultural information exchange centers for American students and scholars pursuing studies abroad. In addition to acting as advisor to the union, he was chairman of the Finance Committee and was a member of the governing board.
Nettleton was made honorary professor of the Ecole Interalliée des Hautes Etudes Socialles in Paris; lecturer (Louis Liard Foundation) at the Sorbonne and at the University of Cambridge; and chevalier of the Legion of Honor (1919).
Nettleton authored a number of works on seventeenth- and eighteenth-century British drama, including English Drama of the Restoration and Eighteenth Century (1914) and The Drama and the Stage. He also edited Specimens of the Short Story (1901), The Major Dramas of Richard Brinsley Sheridan (1906), Old Testament Narratives (1909), The Book of the Yale Pageant (1916), Twelfth Night (Yale Shakespeare) (1921), Yale in the World War (1925), and British Dramatists from Dryden to Sheridan (1939).
George Nettleton married Mary Clark Treat in 1902. They were the parents of Edward Treat and Mary Treat Nettleton. George Nettleton died in 1959.
Americans -- France; Literature -- History and criticism; World War, 1914-1918 -- United States; Educators; Bliss, Robert Woods, 1875-1962; Cunliffe, John William, 1865-1946; Krans, H. S.; Lansingh, Van Resselaer; Nettleton, Anna Tucker, 1872-1949; Nettleton, George Henry, 1874-1959; Haight, Mary Treat Nettleton; Nettleton, Mary Ellen Tucker; Phelps, Annabel Hubbard, -1939; Phelps, William Lyon, 1865-1943; Stokes, Anson Phelps, 1874-1958; Thompson, Henry B.; Tucker, J. T. (Joshua Thomas), 1812-1897; Van Dyke, Paul; American University Union in Europe. Yale Bureau; Yale College (1887- ). Class of 1896; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- History; Yale University -- Students
- Correspondence, 1884-1955; Series I; 8.75 linear feet (18 boxes)
  Scope and Contents
  The series contains two subseries: Personal Correspondence and Professional Correspondence. Each subseries is arranged chronologically. Undated material is arranged alphabetically by sender at the end of each subseries.
  - Personal Correspondence
    - 1884-1892 (Box 1, Folder 1-15)
    - 1893 January 4 - 1893 April 20 (Box 2, Folder 16-29)
    - 1893 April 21 - 1893 November 21 (Box 3, Folder 30-44)
    - 1893 November 22 - 1894 July 18 (Box 4, Folder 45-56)
    - 1894 September 24 - 1894 November 25 (Box 5, Folder 57-70)
    - 1894 November 27 - 1895 June 9 (Box 6, Folder 71-84)
    - 1895 June 11 - 1896 March 1 (Box 7, Folder 85-96)
    - 1896 March 4 - 1896 December 17 (Box 8, Folder 97-108)
    - 1897 January 6 - 1898 February 21 (Box 9, Folder 109-121)
    - 1898 February 22 - 1911 December 21 (Box 10, Folder 122-133)
    - 1912 July 3 - 1918 June 26 (Box 11, Folder 134-147)
    - 1918 June 27 - 1931 May 10 (Box 12, Folder 148-162)
    - 1931 September 17 - 1950 January 1 (Box 13, Folder 163-165)
    - Undated
      - A - Nettleton, Anna T. (Box 13, Folder 166)
      - Nettleton, Mary (Treat) (Box 13, Folder 167)
      - Nettleton, Mary (Tucker) - Van Dyke (Box 13, Folder 168)
    - Fragments (Box 13, Folder 169)
    - Greeting cards, calling cards, and gift enclosures (Box 13, Folder 170)
  - Professional Correspondence
    - 1903 November 10 - 1919 February 27 (Box 14, Folder 171-185)
    - 1919 March 2 - 1920 March 30 (Box 15, Folder 186-199)
    - 1920 April 1 - 1921 December 23 (Box 16, Folder 200-212)
    - 1922 January 1 - 1929 November 5 (Box 17, Folder 213-227)
    - 1929 November 6 - 1955 November 29 (Box 18, Folder 228-237)
      General
      See also: Photograph of R.B. Sheridan portrait enclosed with V. Connely letter of February 26, 1937, and photograph of B. Currie enclosed with his letter of September 25, 1937; box 30, folder 336
    - Undated, A-W (Box 18, Folder 238)
    - Fragments (Box 18, Folder 239)
- Subject Files, 1917-1945; Series II; 1.75 linear feet (4 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - American University Union (A.U.U.)
    - Minutes and reports
      - 1917 December 12 - 1920 August 31 (Box 19, Folder 240)
      - 1920 November 26 - 1925 October 31 (Box 19, Folder 241)
      - 1926 January - 1946 January 17 (Box 19, Folder 242)
      - Undated (Box 19, Folder 243)
    - Financial records
      - 1919 June 14 - 1923 August 31 (Box 19, Folder 244)
      - 1923 March - 1946 (Box 19, Folder 245)
    - A.U.U. - British Division (London)
      - Financial records and reports
        - 1918 April 2 - 1920 December 31 (Box 19, Folder 246)
        - 1921 January 1 - 1922 December 31 (Box 19, Folder 247)
        - 1923 January 31 - 1924 April 1 (Box 19, Folder 248)
        - 1925 January 1 - 1937 November (Box 20, Folder 249)
        - Undated (Box 20, Folder 250)
    - A.U.U. - Continental Division (Paris)
      - Financial records and reports
        - 1917 November 16 - 1921 December 21 (Box 20, Folder 251)
        - 1922 April - 1923 September 6 (Box 20, Folder 252)
        - 1923 September 10 - 1945 December 10 (Box 20, Folder 253)
        - Undated (Box 20, Folder 254)
    - Maison des Etudiants
      - Financial records and reports
        - 1919 January 20; undated (Box 20, Folder 255)
    - War Memorial Fund
      - Financial records and reports
        - 1921 May 27 - 1929 January 3 (Box 20, Folder 256)
        - 1929 April 15 - 1937 June 30 (Box 20, Folder 257)
        - Account book, 1920-1935 (Box 20, Folder 258)
        - Account book, 1922-1934 (Box 21, Folder 259)
        - Pass book, 1924-1933 (Box 21, Folder 260)
    - Yale Bureau in Paris
      - Financial records and reports
        - 1917 June 12 - 1918 May 2 (Box 21, Folder 261)
        - 1918 May 14 - 1919 April 3; undated (Box 21, Folder 262)
        - Account book, 1917-1919 (Box 21, Folder 263)
        - Cash book of C.W. Mendell, undated (Box 21, Folder 264)
        - Guest register, 1917-1919 (Box 21, Folder 265)
  - Yale University
    - Committee on General Education, 1923-1924 (Box 22, Folder 266)
    - Course of Study Committee, 1934, undated (Box 22, Folder 267)
    - Dean's Reports, 1937-1939 (Box 22, Folder 268)
    - English course exam questions, 1926-1942; undated (Box 22, Folder 269)
    - English Department "Suggestions,", 1919 (Box 22, Folder 270)
- Diaries, 1899-1956; Series III; 2.5 linear feet (5 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged chronologically.
  - 1899 July 1 - 1899 August 29 (Box 23, Folder 271)
  - 1907 January 25 - 1909 December 31 (Box 23, Folder 272-273)
  - 1911 January 1 - 1911 December 22 (Box 23, Folder 273)
  - 1913 January 1 - 1913 July 30 (Box 23, Folder 274)
  - 1914 January 15 - 1914 December 31 (Box 23, Folder 275)
  - 1916 January 1 - 1916 December 20 (Box 23, Folder 275)
  - 1917 February 5 - 1918 January 9 (Box 23, Folder 276-277)
  - 1918 January 10 - 1919 December 13 (Box 24, Folder 278)
  - 1920 July 24 - 1920 July 31 (Box 24, Folder 279)
  - 1924 April 19 - 1924 June 3 (Box 24, Folder 279)
  - 1931 January 1 - 1931 December 15 (Box 24, Folder 280)
  - 1933 April 1 - 1933 July 16 (Box 24, Folder 280)
  - 1935 March 14 - 1936 December 18 (Box 24, Folder 281)
  - 1938 January 6 - 1938 December 3 (Box 24, Folder 282)
  - 1939 January 1 - 1939 December 19 (Box 24, Folder 282)
  - 1940 January 20 - 1940 November 14 (Box 25, Folder 283)
  - 1941 January 1 - 1941 June 22 (Box 25, Folder 283)
  - 1942 January 1 - 1942 December 23 (Box 25, Folder 284)
  - 1943 January 6 - 1943 December 30 (Box 25, Folder 284)
  - 1944 January 1 - 1947 December 31 (Box 25, Folder 285-286)
  - 1948 January 1 - 1953 December 31 (Box 26, Folder 287-289)
  - 1954 January 1 - 1955 December 25 (Box 27, Folder 290-291)
  - 1956 January 1 - 1956 May 16 (Box 27, Folder 292)
- Speeches and Writings, 1915-1951; Series IV; 1 linear feet (2 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically within the subseries Articles, Speeches, and Books. Fragments, notes, and miscellaneous writings are located at the end of the series.
  - Articles
    - "Albinia, Countess of Buckinghamshire, and the School for Scandal, undated (Box 28, Folder 293)
    - 'IV "The Camp"' from F. W. Bateson, 1935 (Box 28, Folder 294)
    - " Robinson Crusoe: Sheridan's Drury Lane Pantomime - I", 1943 (Box 28, Folder 295)
    - "Sheridan's Robinson Crusoe: the Newcastle Version of 1791-II", undated (Box 28, Folder 296)
    - "Sheridan's St. Patrick's Day ", undated (Box 28, Folder 297)
  - Speeches
    - "Americans in France,", 1917 (Box 28, Folder 298)
    - Les anciens élèves, undated (Box 28, Folder 299)
    - "France and the Humanities,", 1943 (Box 28, Folder 300)
    - "The Franco-American Rapprochment,", undated (Box 28, Folder 301)
    - Untitled speech given at Louvain, undated (Box 28, Folder 302)
    - Untitled speech relating to French-U.S. relations, undated (Box 28, Folder 303)
    - Untitled speech on Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 1919 (Box 28, Folder 304)
  - Books
    - [ The History of Yale ]
      - Chapters I and II with comments by G. Pierson and H. Boatfield, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 305)
      - Chapters I and II (second copy), undated (Box 28, Folder 306)
      - Chapters I and II with comments by G.P. Krapp, 1915 (Box 28, Folder 307)
      - Chapter III, undated (Box 28, Folder 308)
      - Chapter IV with comments by G.P. Krapp, 1916 (Box 28, Folder 309)
    - Yale in the World War
      - Pages 1-299, 1925 (Box 28, Folder 310-315)
      - Pages 300-797, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 316-323)
      - Editor's note, Role of Honor list, and Note, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 324)
      - Statistics, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 325)
      - Yale War Record, 1925 (Box 29, Folder 326-329)
      - Printed material, 1921, 1926 (Box 29, Folder 330)
    - The Yale Pageant, 1916 (Box 29, Folder 331-332)
    - Fragments and notes, undated (Box 29, Folder 333)
    - Miscellaneous poems, articles, and notes by others, 1939, 1940, undated (Box 29, Folder 334)
- Memorabilia, 1893-1945; Series V; .5 linear feet (2 boxes)
  This series contains material arranged alphabetically by type of material.
  - Account book, 1893-1894 (Box 30, Folder 335)
  - Photographs
    - American University Union, undated (Box 30, Folder 336)
      See also: box 31, folder 353
    - Individuals and groups, 1910, 1937, undated (Box 30, Folder 337)
    - Nettleton, George H., 1913, 1917, undated (Box 30, Folder 338)
    - World War I memorials, 1928, 1930, undated (Box 30, Folder 339)
  - Postcards
    - Miscellaneous, 1930, undated (Box 30, Folder 340)
    - World War I, 1914-1918, undated (Box 30, Folder 341)
  - Printed material
    - Advertisements, 1894, 1897, undated (Box 30, Folder 342)
    - Clippings
      - American University Union, 1917-1930, undated (Box 30, Folder 343)
      - Nettleton, George H., 1917, 1920, 1924, 1943-1945, undated (Box 30, Folder 344)
      - World Wars I and II, 1918-1921, 1942, undated (Box 30, Folder 345)
      - Miscellaneous, 1909, 1916-1943, undated (Box 30, Folder 346)
    - Personal mementos of George Nettleton, 1919, 1930, undated (Box 30, Folder 347)
    - Poster, "Pour quoi les américans..." (Box 32)
      General note
      See: MG Common Folio, box 3 folder 62
    - Programs, menus, etc., 1896-1964 (Box 30, Folder 348)
    - Publications
      - University brochures, 1917-1944 (Box 30, Folder 349)
      - World War I, 1915-1919; undated (Box 30, Folder 350)
      - Qu'est-ce que c'est ?, 1919 March - June (Box 31, Folder 351)
      - VOILA!, 1919 April - June (Box 31, Folder 352)
  - Oversized photographs of the American University Union, undated (Box 31, Folder 353)
- Additional material, 1913-1959 (inclusive), 1913-1939 (bulk); Accession 1996-M-102
  This addition contains material relating to Edward T. Nettleton, son of George H. Nettleton.
  - Nettleton, Edward T.
    - Correspondence
      - To family members, general, 1921-1939, 1943, [1953?], undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - To Mrs. George H. Nettleton (mother), 1921-1926, 1936-1943 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - From friends, 1921, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Letters of condolence to the family at the death of George H. Nettleton, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Memorabilia, 1913, 1922-1928, 1943-1944, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
      See also: enclosure with letter dated 1924 May 9, box 1, folder 1
    - School records, 1913-1916, 1921-1922 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Additional material, 1819-1934; Accession 1988-M-050
  - Edward Payson Nettleton diaries, 1857-1888 (Box 1, Folder 1-6)
  - Mary E. Tucker (Nettleton) diaries, Circa 1857-1906 (Box 1, Folder 7-14)
    Flyleaf of Folder 7 diary signed "Brig. Gen. S. C. Armstrong" (Samuel Chapman?), "Honololu"; last pages of this diary sewn shut at a later date
    Folder 8 diary contains small envelopes with baby's hair and closer from baby's grave
    FOlder 13 diary contains a baby photo, possibly of George Henry Nettleton, as well as a receipt of payment to Dr. Benjamin Cushing for the delivery of baby George Henry Nettleton
  - Ann D. Tucker trust ledger (from Mary), Circa 1898 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Anna Tucker Nettleton childhood diary, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Anna Tucker Nettleton trip diaries and photo albums, 1902-1909, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 17-23)
  - Edward Payson Nettleton, moot court briefs and arguments, 1866-1867 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Account ledger, 1819-1830 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Amos Sherman Treat (et al.), letters and notices received, 1831-1853 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Amos Sherman Treat, letters received, 1835-1854 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Amos Sherman Treat, letters received, 1837-1857 (Box 2, Folder 3-4)
  - Amos Sherman Treat, letters received, 1847-1872 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Amos Sherman Treat, letters and photograph, 1847-1879 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - A. Treat and M. A. Clark, letters, 1862-1882 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Mary Brown Treat, letters, 1840s-1860s (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Mary Clark Treat, Mrs. Amos Sherman Treat, letters and photograph, 1861, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Harman Treat, letters, 1846, 1852 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Harvey Treat, letters, 1847 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Treat family letters and newspaper clippings, 1850s-1860s, 1960 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Nettleton family miscellaneous correspondence, 1880s (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Amos Sherman Treat, Citizens Water Co. incorporation hearing minutes, 1886 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1852, 1889, 1895, 1902 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Miscellaneous family papers, 1870s-1880s (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Includes a manuscript Memorial Day address by an unidentified author and Nettleton family printed material and legal and financial documents
  - Joshua Thomas Tucker diaries, 1850-1897 (Box 3, Folder 1-16)
  - Joshua Thomas Tucker, Afloat and Ashore: Notes of Travel in 1859, printed edition and manuscript, 1859-1861 (Box 3, Folder 17-20)
  - Ann Deborah Shackford (Tucker) letters, photographs, and ephemera, 1853, 1866-1868, undated (Box 3, Folder 21-25)
  - George Henry Nettleton, notes on family property and material in the Nettleton Papers, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - LaFarge family New Year's performance ephemera, Circa 1920 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Joshua Thomas Tucker correspondence, 1840-1878 (Box 4, Folder 1-24)
  - Joshua Thomas Tucker correspondence, 1879-1897, undated (Box 5, Folder 1-10)
- Additional material, 1917-1964, undated; Accession 2003-M-038
  - Correspondence
    - Dewick, Alfred to Mary Nettleton, 1933 July 14 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Long, Janet to Mary and Gordon Haight, 1938 July 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Nettleton, Anna T. to George Nettleton, 1917 July 26 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Nettleton, George
      - To daughter Mary Nettleton, 1920, [1929] (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - To his wife Mary Nettleton, 1933 May (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Nettleton, Mrs. George (Mary) (Box 1)
      - To husband George Nettleton, 1936 July 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
      - To daughter Mary Nettleton, 1927, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      - Address book with enclosed correspondence and notes, 1957, 1963, 1964, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Nettleton, Mary
      - To Edward Nettleton, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - To father George Nettleton, 1928, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - To mother Mrs. George (Mary) Nettleton, 1921-1936, undated (Box 1, Folder 11 - 12)
      - To her family, 1932, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - To her parents, 1922, 1925, 1938, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Unidentified birthday card, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Nettleton, Mary Treat to "Aunt Mary [Haight]", 1944 April 3 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Nettleton, Minot to "Aunt Mary and Uncle Gordon [Haight]", 1944 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Sanford, Julia Treat to Mary Nettleton, 1933 June 9 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Treat, Frances M. [Fannie] to Mary Nettleton, n.y. October 5 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - ----, Cousin Alice to Mary Nettleton, n.y. July 15 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Invitation to a dance held by the Nettleton's and the McLanahan's, n.y. October 16 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Personal papers of George Nettleton
    - Bibliography, 0 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Birthday telegrams, 1954 July 16, 18, undated (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Freshman year accounts, 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Poem by Frederick Sheffield for George Nettleton's birthday, 1954 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Secret society meeting notes (C of J), 1903 March 31 (Box 1, Folder 27)